Holloway-Amiss-Leavell Society Papers, 1902-1977
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Holloway-Amiss-Leavell Society Papers 1902-1977
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1998-012
1 box; 0.5 cu. ft.
The papers consist of genealogical information about the Holloway, Amiss, and Leavell families, as well as other families that intermarried with them.
Holloway-Amiss-Leavell family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Holloway-Amiss-Leavell Society Papers were donated to Special Collections in September 1998.
Historical Information
The Holloway-Amiss-Leavell Society was organized in 1937. The Amiss family's origins are uncertain, but can be dated to the late 1600s settlement in Culpeper, Essex, and Middlesex counties, Virginia, and Granville County, North Carolina. The Leavell family originated with John LaVelle (1675-1740), who was born in France and lived in Virginia, probably in York County, on or before 1715.
For more information about the family and society, see The Holloway-Amiss-Leavell Family (Holloway-Amiss-Leavell Society, 1952). A copy of this book is available for use in Special Collections: Spec Large CS 71 .H745 1952.
Scope and Content
The papers consist of genealogical information about the Holloway, Amiss, and Leavell families, as well as other families that intermarried with them.
Arrangement
The papers are organized under family name, followed by a general miscellany of records.
Contents List
- Amiss family chart. (Box-folder 1-1)
- Amiss family genealogy (1710-1979), [1979]. (Box-folder 1-2)
- Ball family genealogy (1638-1799). (Box-folder 1-3)
- Recollections by Bathurst Brown Bagsby, 1950. (Box-folder 1-4)
- Bayse family genealogy (1645-1977), [1977]. (Box-folder 1-5)
- Blake family application for membership in the National Society of Sons/ Daughters of American Colonists. (Box-folder 1-6)
- Individual Line through Nicholas Browning. (Box-folder 1-7)
- "Genealogy of the Brownings in America," (1621-1908). (Box-folder 1-8)
- Genealogy of the Davis Family (1660-1932). (Box-folder 1-9)
- Reminscences by Buford Eastham, June 5, 1977. (Box-folder 1-10)
- Genealogy of the Eastham family (1637-1978), 1978. (Box-folder 1-11)
- "Horses - A way of life for the Easthams." (Box-folder 1-12)
- Eastham - Copy of wills, abstract titles, heirs. (Box-folder 1-13)
- Listing of Johnston family members in the Culpepper County Will Book. (Box-folder 1-14)
- Burwell Leavell (1775-1847). (Box-folder 1-15)
- Descendants of Burwell Leavell, 1976. (Box-folder 1-16)
- Miscellaneous information on the Burwell Leavell family. (Box-folder 1-17)
- Records of John C. Leavell's Family, 1958-1961. (Box-folder 1-18)
- Will of Burwell Leavell and revolutionary record of John Leavell. (Box-folder 1-19)
- Capt. John Menefee family Bible records (1770-1845), 1937, n.d. (Box-folder 1-20)
- Genealogy of the Miller Family of Rappahannock County, Virginia, 1901. (Box-folder 1-21)
- Genealogy of the Norman-Courtney-Johnston families, 1979, n.d. (Box-folder 1-22)
- Genealogy of the Norman family (1726-1978), [1978]. (Box-folder 1-23)
- Person's Lineage—compiled by George Fuller Walker, 1963, n.d. (Box-folder 1-24)
- Genealogy of the Price family. (Box-folder 1-25)
- Genealogy of the Roberts family. (Box-folder 1-26)
- Genealogy of the Russell family (1660-1978), [1978]. (Box-folder 1-27)
- Genealogy of the Taylor family of Southampton, Surry County, Virginia, (1700-1932). (Box-folder 1-28)
- Mrs. Kerenhappuch Turner (a heroine of 1776)—an address by G.S. Bradshaw, 1902. (Box-folder 1-29)
- Register of christenings, baptisms, marriages, deaths in St. Mark's Parish, Culpepper, Virginia, (1794-1840). (Box-folder 1-30)
- Virginia Colonial Abstracts—Lancaster County. (Box-folder 1-31)
- Madison County, Virginia Index Records. (Box-folder 1-32)
- Rockbridge County, Virginia Index records. (Box-folder 1-33)
- 1810 Census of Spotsylvania, Virginia. (Box-folder 1-34)
- "Old records revel 'Gentlemen Justices.'" (Box-folder 1-35)
- "Sources of North Carolina research—where to find them," December 1961. (Box-folder 1-36)
- Speech notes. (Box-folder 1-37)
- Society meetings, 1952-1958. (Box-folder 1-38)